Arpith M

marpith56@gmail.com | 6360163806 | Banglore

SUMMARY

Versatile DevOps Engineer with 3.5 years of experience. To be associated with progressive organization which provides me the best platform that utilizes my skills and abilities to the fullest for development of the self and the firm.

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer, Test Yantra Sofware Services

May 2021 - Present

As DevOps Engineer, owning design and implementation plan for CI/CD deployment for all the services on IaaP Cloud Platform - AWS.

We have created POCs for two financial clients of TestYantra

Technical Consultant, Samartha Info Solutions

Mar 2018 - May 2021

As DevOps Engineerowning design and development, development environment setup, mentoring, implementation plan for CI/CD deployment for all the services on IaaP Cloud Platform - AWS.

- Have in-depth knowledge of Linux OS & Administration. Extensive working knowledge of AWS: including Design, Deployment, Administration, S3, EC2, Load Balancers, Auto-scaling, High availability solutions, Cloud Formations.
- Hands-on experience designing, building, and operating scalable IT infrastructures in AWS cloud.
- Thorough knowledge on installation/configuration of Jenkins. Plugins installation, Configuration of pipelines, setting up manual gates, security, ssh keys etc.
- Excellent knowledge in version control tools Git/Git hub check in, checkout, branching, creating ORG/Repos
- Experienced in providing day-to-day user administration like adding/deleting users in local and global groups on Red Hat Linux platform and managing user's queries.
- Maintaining the Security groups and setting up the rules for instances that are associated to the security groups.
- Experienced in working with version control systems like GIT and used Source code management client tools like GitBash, GitHub, Git Lab
- Proficient in integrating code quality tools SonarQube and Jfrog artifactory
- Extensive working experience in setting up multiple domains, clustering, load balancing and configuring resources
- Experience in container-based technologies like **Docker**.
- Expertise in writing scripts to handle complex automation / administration tasks using Shell scripting.
- Proficient in deployments and troubleshooting issues with JAR, WAR and EAR files in single node and clustered environments.

- Experience in configuring code analysis, code coverage tools like SonarQube as part of DevOps pipeline. Integrated **SonarQube** with Maven, configured quality gates, profiles
- Expertise in installation, configuration, and administration of Apache Tomcat server
- Configuring and deploying EC2 instances behind Auto Scaling & ELB
- Configuring and monitoring Cloud Watch metrics & setting Alarms.
- Working with AWS services: elb, efs, vpc, route 53, auto scaling, iam, s3, and glacier.
- Strong understanding of AWS services, such as EC2, Route53, IAM, and ELB
- Hands-on experience on AWS services EC2, VPC, RDS, ELB, S3, Cloud watch.

PROJECTS

Designing AWS Architecture with Continous Deployments

Responsibilities

- Defined AWS Security Groups which acted as virtual firewalls that controlled the traffic allowed reaching one or more AWS EC2 instances.
- Building customized Amazon Machine Images (AMI), Build instances and configures them as per requirements.
- Configure Elastic Load Balancer (ELB) for distribution incoming application traffic across multiple EC2 instances.
- Creating AMIs, Snapshots, and Volumes and managing EBS Volumes.
- Creating Elastic IPs attaching and detaching to instances as per client request.
- Configuring Load balancer and Auto Scaling group. Configuration monitoring for AWS in Cloud Watch. Scale in and out using Auto scale, add and remove instances as needed to handle the growing workload.
- Configuring and Networking of Virtual Private Cloud (VPC). Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets make connection between different zones.
- Experience in writing **Ansible** playbooks to automate infrastructure creation, configuration and operation changes with help of modules in playbooks.

Creating CI/CD pipelines and POC's

Responsibilities:

- As DevOps Engineer, I implemented **Jenkins Pipeline** for Continous Integration and Continous Deployment.
- Created **Dockefiles** to create custom images for deploying the applications.
- Created high available architecture using Terraform
- Experience in Weblogic and Tomcat
- We have created POCs for two financial clients of TestYantra

EDUCATION

BE, Electronics & Communications

Jul 2013 - Jul 2017

Percentage: 67%

Vidya Vikas Institute of Engineering and technology

SKILLS

Cloud Technology: AWS

CI/CD Tool: Jenkins **Container**: Docker

Configuration & Automation Tool: Ansible, Terraform

Scripting: Shell Scripting

Orchestration: Docker Swarm

Web & Application Servers: Tomcat, Weblogic

OS: Linux

Web Servers: Nginx, Tomcat

CERTIFICATIONS

• AWS Solution Architect -Associate : Feb 2020 - Feb 2023